Joseph Borrell, the EU foreign policy chief, said that he expects EU leaders to work toward a call for a humanitarian pause in what's happening in Gaza to bring in some aid.
Is the United States in conversations with the Europeans about that? Would the United States support such a call?
We are in conversations with the Europeans about this question of getting humanitarian aid in,
and we are in conversations with the government of Israel and the government of Egypt about how best to get humanitarian aid in.
But I think with this question, whether you call it a pause or whether you call it a ceasefire,
you have to think about what that would mean in this context when Israel has suffered this terrorist attack and Israel continues to suffer ongoing terrorist attacks.
There are rockets, as I said a moment ago, that continue to be launched from Gaza targeting Israel.
Any ceasefire would give Hamas the ability to rest, to refit, and to get ready to continue launching terrorist attacks against Israel.
You can understand perfectly clearly why that's an intolerable situation for Israel,
as it would be an intolerable situation for any country that has suffered such a brutal terrorist attack
and continues to see the terrorist threat right on its borders.
So what we will continue to do with respect to this question is focus on getting humanitarian assistance in to Gaza.
We've seen deliveries go in for the past three days, and our special envoy on the ground, David Satterfield,
is working intensively to establish ongoing mechanisms for the delivery of humanitarian assistance,
and we're working to establish places where civilians can be safe from harm.
Thank you.